## Joseph C. Dillard, GIS Solutions Architect

Rockwall, Texas, 254-266-5410, joseph.dillard@outlook.com

### **PROFILE**

Driven goal-oriented GIS Architect with over 22 years GIS experience, 17 years Designing, Building, and Maintaining Enterprise GIS Systems, 9 years experience in Java and GIS Web Development. Highly Skilled in most Esri ArcGIS Desktop and Server Products. U.S. Army Veteran.

### EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Aug 2021 — Present

## Scientist, System Engineer - Enterprise GIS Architect, L3Harris

Greenville, TX

U.S. Forces Korea

Design and Configure Open Source GIS Server Systems for Internal Research and Development Effort's.

Use Case and Requirement Gathering from Commercial and Internal Developed Legacy Enterprise System's for new system's under development.

Assisted with Research and Testing of Commercial GIS Server Software to be used in SIGINIT system's.

Jan 2013 — May 2021

# Systems Architecture T4 - Web Developer T4 (SME GIS), CACI International Inc.

Architect and Lead Developer for a GIS-based Situational Awareness System used by the Pacific Air Forces and U.S. Forces Korea. The GIS-based system has over 50+ applications built for different user communities within the Pacific Air Forces and USFK organizations. Combines into a single map view and dashboards that help users aggregate information to report to commanders at different echelons to help make more informed decisions. Users now spend more time analyzing data to make decisions and less time trying to track down information.

Custom applications built using Java, Grails, Spring Boot, Spring Security, Angular 5+, and PrimeNG. Grails has many benefits, one being Increased Developer Productivity which means quicker response to changing client requirements in an Agile environment. The other languages and frameworks listed integrate nicely with Grails and most importantly help meet the customers' requirements for various applications.

Load balancing across 14 ArcGIS Servers and 7 Web Servers running custom Tomcat Load Balancing with 8 Tomcat instances per web server. Zero downtime due to technical failure of the system during major training events with up to 2900 unique users. Previous similar systems outside of this project had a history of not performing well during these events due to the number of users. The system has been observed handling 20,000 ArcGIS Server requests per minute.

Designed the system architecture through four versions of the system over 8 years.

Selected all server and network hardware used for the system ensuring compatibility with the network and planning ahead for system growth.

Provide Technical Direction and Mentoring to members of the team, including System Administrator, Web Developer, and GIS Administrators maintaining the ArcGIS Services and GIS data stored in SDE/Oracle.

"Unique ability to help Product Owners create requirements for their application when they do not understand what they need in the application or what its workflow should be". "Quote from my Manager Karen Munroe"

Worked with COR to communicate the advantages of an agile approach for management of development projects Minimum Viable Product, Dev Sprints, consistent engagement with the Product Owners helped develop better applications, in shorter time periods while minimizing unneeded requirements.

As a team player, I consistently seek other team member's thoughts on technical decisions, ideas, and problems.

Feb 2004 — Jan 2013

## Senior GIS Analyst - GIS System Administrator, CACI International Inc.

Osan Air Base, Korea

Served as Web Admin for ArcGIS ArcIMS/IMF and ArcGIS Servers on multiple networks.

Held primary responsibility for the administration of ArcSDE Oracle database servers on multiple networks.

Assisted and Lead Architecture changes to the system hardware and software configuration multiple times over the life of the system.

Deliver 24/7 technical support ensuring optimal system configuration and connectivity.

Perform geospatial data development in support of the Expeditionary (GeoReach) component of the Air Force GIS Enterprise System.

Maintain/disseminate geospatial data leveraging Air Force Enterprise GIS Architecture.

System Administration of Windows Servers and VMware vSphere virtual machines.

Delivered exercise and/or contingency support as required.

Commercial and NGA Imagery processing using ERDAS IMAGINE

Provided Limited Trimble Survey Support

### Apr 2000 — Feb 2004

### Production Manager and GEOINT Analyst, U.S. Army

U.S. Army

Delivered managerial oversight for mission-critical design and development of GIS-driven solutions and map-based products.

Provided greater productivity, enhanced training capabilities, better collaboration, and improved access to critical information.

Supervised personnel and provided technical guidance in support of their duties.

Delivered high-level technical expertise and generated detailed end-user documentation for advanced imagery systems.

Authored new standard operating procedures for the production of GIS products.

Utilized multiple databases for managing aerial photographs, maps, digital databases, and collateral source materials.

Played a key role in the accurate development of more than 375 GIS and map-based documents.

Efficiently directed a wide range of cartographic and terrain analysis duties.

Ensured quality assurance during all stages of topographic operations.

Operated imagery equipment produced GIS maps and products and supported operational missions.

Trained personnel on the proper and effective use of imagery and GIS equipment.

Successfully increased department productivity and streamlined operations through intensive training efforts.

CVIIIC	A.:1. C D 1	E	Ť	E
SKILLS	Agile Scrum Development	Experienced	Java	Experienced
	Amazon Web Services (AWS)	Novice	JavaScript	Experienced
	Angular 5+	Experienced	Lucidchart	Skillful
	Apache Kafka - ETL Tool	Skillful	Microsoft Azure	Beginner
	Apache Tomcat	Expert	Microsoft Hyper-V	Experienced
	ArcGIS Event Server	Experienced	Microsoft Windows Server	Experienced
	ArcGIS JSAPI	Experienced	MySQL	Expert
	ArcGIS Portal	Experienced	NodeJS	Skillful
	ArcGIS Server	Expert	Oracle Database 11g/12c	Expert
	ArcSDE	Expert	Postgres	Skillful
	Atlassian Jira/Confluence	Experienced	PrimeNG	Experienced
	Docker	Skillful	Python	Experienced
	Eclipse IDE	Experienced	Risk Management Framework	Skillful
	Enterprise GIS Architecture	Expert	(RMF)	
	ERDAS IMAGINE	Skillful	SOA - REST and SOAP	Skillful
	Git - Github	Experienced	SQL - PL/SQL	Expert
	Gradle - Maven	Experienced	Spring Boot	Skillful
	Grails	Expert	Spring Security	Experienced
	Hibernate - GORM	Experienced	UML	Skillful
	HTML & CSS	Expert	Unix - Linux Operating Systems	Skillful
	IntelliJ IDEA	Expert	Visual Studio Code	Expert
	menij i <i>DLA</i>	Lapeit	VMware vSphere	Experienced

SKILLS LEGEND Least to Most: Beginner - Novice - Skillful - Experienced - Expert

EDUCATION				
2012 — 2013	Web Development, Western Governors University			
2000 — 2000	Geographic Information Sciences, National Geospatial Intelligence College			
Aug 2020 — Aug 2023	Security+ CE			
	Current DOD 8570 cert			
Mar 2018	Attended Esri Developers Conference March 2018 Palm Springs California			
Jun 2018	Active Secret Security Clearance			
LINKS	LinkedIn Profile			
	https://www.linkedin.com/in/joe-dillard-gis-architect/			
	Article GeoBase Mission Command System  Air Force Public  Affairs			
	Article describing the system I designed and built as the Architect and Lead Developer, This is an earlier version of the system, about three years into development in 2016. I am quoted in the 6th paragraph. Article as a whole describes part of the system and how it is used.			
	Main Article:			
	https://www.dvidshub.net/news/195988/pacaf-utilizes-geobase-program			
	Two Extra Images with Captions:			
	https://www.dvidshub.net/image/2542634/pacaf-utilizes-geobase-program			

 $\underline{https://www.dvidshub.net/image/2542636/pacaf-utilizes-geobase-program}$ 

 $\underline{https://github.com/JosephDillard/JosephDillard}$ 

Git Hub